# Harish Sista

## (He/Him)

No work authorization required

(201) 310-5683 hsista@stevens.edu 2642 28<sup>th</sup> St, Apt 4F Astoria, NY-11102

#### **SUMMARY**

Ph.D. Candidate researching in ML and NLP with 7+ years of experience working with ML models, Big Data, and Cloud Computing platforms and 2+ years of experience working in a professional environment. Spearheaded an Evidence Extraction and Fact Verification model using Prompt Engineering and tested it with various LLMs. Invented a Black Box Optimization model for online hyperparameter fine-tuning, significantly enhancing model performance in real-time applications.

#### **SKILLS**

Programming Languages	AI Tools	LLMs	Developer APIs	Cloud Platforms	Research Interests
<ul><li>Python</li><li>C++</li><li>Java</li><li>Objective C</li><li>Swift</li><li>SQL</li></ul>	<ul><li>PyTorch</li><li>OpenAI</li><li>HuggingFace</li><li>Transformers</li><li>TensorFlow</li><li>SciKitlearn</li><li>NLTK</li><li>NumPy</li></ul>	<ul><li>GPT</li><li>LLAMA</li><li>MISTRAL</li><li>BLOOM</li><li>BERT-based models</li></ul>	<ul><li>Twitter</li><li>Facebook</li><li>YouTube</li><li>Google</li><li>Amazon</li></ul>	<ul><li>GIT</li><li>PyPA</li><li>AWS</li><li>Google Cloud</li><li>Apple Store</li><li>Heroku</li></ul>	<ul> <li>NLP</li> <li>Prompt</li></ul>

### **EDUCATION**

DLD in Marking Languing (Computer Engineering department)	01/2010 Due
<b>Ph.D. in Machine Learning</b> (Computer Engineering department)	01/2018 - Present
Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken	
M.Eng. in Software Engineering (Electrical Engineering department)	01/2014 - 12/2015
Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken	
B.Eng. in Electronics and Communication Engineering	08/2009 - 05/2013
M.V.S.R Engineering College, Hyderabad, TG, India	

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Infinity Lab, Stevens Institute of Technology - Hoboken, NJ

01/2018 - Present

- Work with various LLMs to address the challenges of Fact Verification using Prompt Engineering, Text Generation, Classification and Evidence Extraction Tasks.
- Invented a Black Box Optimization model for Online Hyperparameter finetuning.
- Built various Python Libraries using Multiprocessing and GPU programming to work efficiently with big datasets.
- Surveyed and implemented various Attention Networks, DNNs and Generative Models to perform NLP tasks of Data Extraction, Modeling, Regression, Ranking, and Classification.
- Collaborated in creating various Scientific, social media, and Misinformation Datasets.
- Developed an AI based iOS application to perform MoCA test for early detection of Alzheimer's.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant, Stevens Institute of Technology - Hoboken, NJ

10/2018 - 09/2019

- Created a chemistry literature dataset for the purpose of similarity search with search queries.
- Preprocessed the dataset, using PDF conversion tools and NLTK library to remove the noise.
- Produced a Novel Generative Ranking Model using Topic Modeling and KeyPhrase analysis, to extract most relevant papers related to the search query.

AI Engineer/iOS Developer, Fresh Digital Group - NY, NY

07/2016 - 06/2017

- Collaborated with Content Writers and Creative Team to individually design and deploy ~30 chat applications for Amazon-Alexa which won appreciation from tech newsletters.
- Developed various iOS, iMessage and tvOS applications in conjunction with several teams.
- Helped company obtain a preferred partnership with Amazon-Alexa and launching partnership with Microsoft-Cortana.